Silence, puny audience!
And welcome to Who Dares To Be A Millionaire?
Tremble before
Morbo's mighty likability,
as I chitchat with our first
contestant, Philip J. Fry.
Give him hell, Morbo!
Prepare for pleasantries!
So, Fry, what do you
do for a living?
Me?
Can I phone a friend?
Chitchat achieved!
Are you ready to play?
I didn't come to play,
I came to win.
Now let's play.
For $1, what tool is
used to hammer a nail?
Is it, A, a hammer?
B, a nail?
C...
B, Nail! Final answer!
Sweet dodo
of Lesotho!
Don't you ever stop to think
before you speak?
I never stop to
think about it.
Leave Fry alone. His intelligence
is just a little differenty.
You a big dummy!
Hey, I'm beginning to think you
guys don't think I'm very smart.
You can barely remember
your own name, Einstein.
Einstein is a hard name
to remember.
Ow!
Smeesh, Professor.
Don't have a shmaneurysm.
Fry's your distant relative.
Not distant enough.
I'll be a monkey's uncle
if I'm this monkey's nephew.
But you're
my only family.
Who will hug me if
I achieve something?
Oh, perhaps
I've been too harsh.
Come, lad, take my hand and I'll
explain why I find you so repugnant.
All my life, I've been
inspired by great minds.
Euclid, Copernicus, Braino.
And my personal role model,
Leonardo da Vinci.
What turned them to stone?
Da Vinci was history's
greatest artist and inventor.
Voilа!
He invented flying machines,
war engines, submarines.
Uh-oh. Nibbler died in the wall.
That's not Nibbler. That's
my most precious possession.
Leonardo's beard!
I paid a fortune for it at an
auction of historic body parts.
I suppose if I have
an Achilles' heel,
it's because I bought it
at that same auction.
Indeed so.
Most indeededly.
Careful with that,
you fool!
No! No!
But possibly yes.
What is it, Professor?
Oh, my! It's da Vinci's
fabled lost invention.
Even the scholars who wrote of this
device had no idea what it was for.
And now, at last,
neither do I!
Maybe we can
figure it out.
We?
Well, I may not
have brain smarts,
but at least
I have street smarts.
I was in the hospital two
weeks. No one visited me.
Quiet, you!
I'm trying to deduce the function
of da Vinci's lost invention.
Not even a card.
He might have hidden a clue
in one of his other works.
Ergo, I sent Bender out for
a copy of The Last Supper.
I'm back!
Everybody at Kinko's was an idiot,
so I just brought the original.
Jesus Christ,
and his 12 Apostles.
That's odd.
This hand here doesn't
belong to anybody.
And it's pointing a knife
at James the Lesser!
That's the great thing
about that hand.
And what about
these funky table legs?
It's like they're from
some other, funkier painting.
Maybe da Vinci painted
over something else.
It's called a pentimento.
That's true, Dr. Zoidberg.
How did you know that?
My doctorate is
in art history.
Let's see what's
under The Last Supper.
Wait a second! I'm not big-boned, I'm just fat.
My God! Look!
My God! I'm looking!
My God! Saint James was a robot!
My God! Da Vinci left his
legs unpainted as a clue.
My God! This is the greatest mystery of all time.
We must fly to Rome and
exhume the body of Saint James.
Didn't we used to be a
delivery company? To the ship.
Psst.
Leela, wanna join
the mile-deep club?
Sure, why not?
No time!
I've found a clue that
could unlock all
the secrets of history.
Look at these
Roman numerals.
Roman numerals?
I've got it!
We're in Rome!
Don't be stupid. It's a
long-lost mathematical code.
I'll need to consult
these ancient writings.
Some preposterous hogwash
about the Fibonacci sequence...
Aha!
The markings indicate how
many paces we need to take.
One... Okay,
we're there.
Brothers and sisters,
let us pry.
It's true! Saint James
really was a robot.
I bet he's up in robot heaven right
now. So he won't miss his eyes.
My God! Robot Saint
James is a zombie.
Nay, I am not Saint James.
Enough of your lies,
Saint James.
We saw you in
The Last Supper.
The great man Leonardo built
me as an artist's model.
When I took repose
in this coffin,
I carefully tossed the real
Saint James in yonder heap.
I'm sure you have
many questions.
Come, there is a chamber where I used to
speak with Pope John
the Patient.
I told him I'd be
back in five minutes.
Well, he'll make
a nice heap.
I am Animatronio, guardian
of da Vinci's great secret.
He left my legs visible
in the painting as a clue,
then dispatched me
hither to await
his shadow society
of intellectuals.
Hi, Animatronio.
You personally
knew da Vinci?
Was he nice?
How did his hair smell?
And on a personal note, what
is the function of this device?
Halt! You know not the function
of the machina magnifica?
Then thou art not members
of the shadow society!
The what now?
Not one more word
shall I breathe.
Not even about the great fountain
where thou mayest find the...
Wait...
Thou didst not know about
the fountain, didst thou?
Curses!
I must be punished.
Quick, we must
find out what he knows
before he flays
himself to death!
Where is the
great fountain?
What makes it so great?
Why does a robot
need a codpiece?
Fie, thou
fen-suckled bum-bailey!
Thou willst never pry information
from these mechanical lips!
Just tell us, already.
Okay, the fountain
thou seekest is...
And so dies our hope
of solving this mystery.
Come on, gang.
Let's go home.
Wait! Let's not
give up so easily.
Animatronio
mentioned a fountain.
That's a statue of Neptune,
god of water.
The number of points on his
trident is three, or trey.
The "U" in his name
is written like "V".
Trey, "V".
Trevi!
It's the Trevi fountain!
There can be no question! But, Professor...
There can be no question!
Wow, it hasn't changed
in 1,000 years.
Okay, everyone,
into the fountain.
What are you, senile?
I'm not jumping in there.
Hey, look. Coins.
I got 48 cents.
There's one more nickel,
and it's a big one!
Quickly,
into the sewer hole.
Why?
What's this dump?
My God!
It's the Pantheon!
This place is
3,000 years old.
What could possibly
be left to discover?
Maybe something
about ourselves, Leela.
Wait!
What's under that blanket?
My God!
Da Vinci's Vitruvian Man!
It's truly a masterpiece.
Note how
the perspective lines
draw the eye
right to his dong.
Say, what's this?
Anyone hear something?
It's a coin slot.
Bender,
insert that giant nickel.
Sure.
Hush, Bender!
What's your game,
Vitruvian Man?
Whoa!
I withdraw
the question, Vitruvian Man.
Da Vinci's lost workshop!
At the risk of
sounding stupid,
do these things
actually work?
Of course not, stupid!
I mean, that flying machine's
as aerodynamic as a sofa!
How could it possibly
get off the ground?
In a way thou shalt
never discover!
Hi, Animatronio.
I feign death
and stalk thee,
that I might preserve the
greatest of Leonardo's secrets!
All right, buddy, we want secrets
! And they'd better be ancient!
Never shall I reveal how these
wondrous machines fit together!
They fit together?
I said no such thing.
And then I died!
You're right, Professor.
This thing doesn't fly.
Don't sit in there, you idiot! That's dangerous!
No wonder this contraption isn't aerodynamic!
It's not an aircraft,
it's a spacecraft!
As I live, thou shan't
discover the great secret!
Bye, Animatronio!
My God!
Why would Leonardo's machine
have brought us here?
I don't know.
Let's ask this guy.
I am Leonardo.
Welcome to Planet Vinci.
My God!
That's what
I was gonna say!
Leonardo!
You're alive? Here?
You've learned my great secret.
I was but a visitor to Earth.
In truth, I am what
you call a space alien.
Oh!
It's an honor to
meet you, Leonardo.
And may I say, you were
great in Titanic. The Beach...
That's Leonardo DiCaprio,
you blockhead!
Looks like eating rocks
wasn't as dumb as you said.
So what do people
do for fun here?
Do you enjoy
partying all night,
with plenty of ale
and lusty women?
I sure do!
Not us.
We spend our leisure time
in the mathematics museum.
Planet Vinci is basically
a single colossal university.
How's your football team?
Learned.
Ooh! I'm going to check out
that math lecture.
All this knowledge is giving me a raging brainer.
Would you like to hear
the lecture, too, Fry?
No. It would just go in one
ear and out some other hole.
Come. Sit down.
Now, that I can do.
I have a terrible secret
to confess, Mr. DiCaprio.
I'm not very smart.
I appreciate your candor.
I don't even know what
language you're speaking.
I, too, have a confession.
You see, here on Planet Vinci,
I am the stupidest person.
What? Who'd possibly
think you're stupid?
Duh! I'm Leonardo!
I don't know the mass
of the Higgs boson.
Duh!
I have to draw in pencil,
'cause I don't know how to
use rendering software.
Stupid Biff!
Thinks he's so smart.
He looks stronger
than you, too.
I went to Earth because I could
no longer stand the ridicule.
But being surrounded by even stupider
people was equally infuriating.
I can see myself
in your shiny button.
Inventing is
what makes me happy.
Or did, until I misplaced
the plans for my masterpiece.
You mean these?
The machina magnifica?
Infinite joy!
Fry, my friend, you have
given my life meaning again!
That calculus lecture
was harder than I expected.
We had to answer every question
in the form of an opera.
I have a lot of
homework for tomorrow,
if I don't want
to be embarrassed.
Thank you. Thank you.
And if you like that,
you'll love our main event.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Leonardo DiCaprio!
I mean, da Vinci!
For centuries, you've ridiculed
me. Especially you, Biff.
Nice hat!
But, at long last, this invention will show you.
It will show you all!
Behold, my unstoppable
doomsday machine!
And I helped!
Wait. You told me it was an
unstoppable ice cream machine.
Ice cream is just a by-product of the machine!
Its primary purpose
is to exterminate
everyone who ever
made me feel inferior!
Ooh! I'm so scared!
Bring it on, dum-dum!
Oh, yeah? Let's see how
hard you're laughing
when my doomsday machine
chops off your face!
Leonardo, stop!
I want in on this!
Are you crazy, Professor?
I hate these nerds!
Just 'cause I'm
stupider than them,
they think they're smarter than me.
Kill them all, starting with the math teacher!
I knew this final invention
would be a humdinger.
Yes. We three idiots will
finally have our revenge!
I don't think so.
You two make me ashamed
to call myself an idiot.
There's always going to be
someone smarter than you,
so the only way to be happy is to
make the most of what you've got.
But you've got nothing.
Oh, no?
I've got one single nail, and
another nail to nail it in with.
And I'm gonna stop this infernal
ice cream machine once and for all!
Some doomsday machine!
It barely killed anyone!
Oh, yeah?
Well, take this!
Oh, my.
Poor Leonardo da Vinci.
He sure was stupid.
Fry, I admire
what you did today,
and I'm deeply sorry for
insulting your intellect.
Your tiny, tiny intellect.
Oops. There I go again,
you dope.
I mean, dummy.
It's okay.
I may not be clever,
but I have a good heart.
That's what my mom
used to say.
She was a wise woman.
Also, that I'm not
much to look at.
A wise woman, indeed.